Finding aid to Smith Club of Philadelphia records CA.MS.00319
Smith College Archives
Smith Club of Philadelphia records
1924-1997
Smith College Archives
Smith Club of Philadelphia
CA.MS.00319
2.917 linear feet (7 containers)
The Smith Club of Philadelphia records contain minutes, membership directories, programs, financial records, and correspondence documenting the club's activities.
Biographical / Historical
The Smith Club of Philadelphia was founded in 1923 with 103 original members. College President William A. Neilson played a large part in organizing many of the club's early programs, which commonly included talks by Smith alumnae and faculty, as well as other local professionals. The club has a history of participating in many Smith alumnae club traditions, such as pecan sales, teas for accepted and graduating students, and scholarship funds for local Smithies. The club has also hosted a number of more unique activities, such as theater benefits from Treasure Island (1924) to Mame (1996).
Scope and Contents
Minutes and correspondence make up the large majority of this collection. Minutes of general and executive board meetings give a detailed record of club business and programs, as well as attendance. The correspondence is between board members, club members, and various members of Smith College faculty and staff. Additionally present are financial records, comprised of treasurer's reports, budgets, and receipts of college and scholarship gifts. Various materials such as program invitations, newspaper clippings, and reports on benefits, scholarships, and seven-college relations are also included.
Conditions Governing Access
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Smith Club of Philadelphia Records were donated over a period of time to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources.
Related Materials
- 90. Alumnae Association
Smith College--Alumni and alumnae--History--Sources
- List of Board Members and Reports on New Jersey Representatives, 1957-72 (Box 1)
- President's Notes and Mailings, 1962-70 (Box 1)
- Minutes, 1924-40 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Correspondence, 1940-52 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous, 1948-49 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous, 1950-51 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous, 1951-52 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Records (2 folders), 1955-58 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Records, 1962-66 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Records, 1966-68 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Records, 1968-70 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Records, 1970-72 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Records, 1972-74 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Records, 1974-76 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Records, 1976-77 (Box 1)
- Minutes and Records, 1977-79 (Box 1)
- Minutes, 1981-86 (Box 2)
- Minutes, 1987-90 (Box 2)
- Minutes, 1991-97 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, 1980s-90s (Box 2)
- Clippings and Program Invitations, 1980s; undated (Box 2)
- Programs/Meetings and Officer Lists, 1982-96 (Box 2)
- Financial Records and Treasurer's Reports, 1982-97 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Minutes and Club Records (1 of 3), 1940-47 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Minutes and Club Records (2 of 3), 1940-47 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Minutes and Club Records (3 of 3), 1940-47 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Club Records (1 of 2), 1946-47 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Club Records (2 of 2), 1946-47 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Minutes (1 of 3), 1953-59 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Minutes (2 of 3), 1953-59 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Minutes (3 of 3), 1953-59 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Club Records (1 of 3), 1952-53 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Club Records (2 of 3), 1952-53 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Club Records (3 of 3), 1952-53 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Club Records (1 of 4), 1954-57 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Club Records (2 of 4), 1954-57 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Club Records (3 of 4), 1954-57 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Club Records (4 of 4), 1954-57 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Club Records (1 of 5), 1958-60 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Club Records (2 of 5), 1958-60 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Club Records (3 of 5), 1958-60 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Club Records (4 of 5), 1958-60 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Club Records (5 of 5), 1958-60 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Minutes (1 of 2), 1959-66 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Minutes (2 of 2), 1959-66 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Minutes (1 of 2), 1979-84 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Minutes (2 of 2), 1979-84 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Minutes and Club Records (1 of 4), 1978-80 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Minutes and Club Records (2 of 4), 1978-80 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Minutes and Club Records (3 of 4), 1978-80 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Minutes and Club Records (4 of 4), 1978-80 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Minutes and Club Records (1 of 3), 1980-82 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Minutes and Club Records (2 of 3), 1980-82 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Minutes and Club Records (3 of 3), 1980-82 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Minutes, 1984-86 (Box 2)
- Notebook - Club Records, 1986-88 (Box 2)
- President's notebooks, 1968-74 (Box 3)
- President's notebooks, 1974-1982 (Box 4)
- Club notebooks, 1924-1979 (Box 5)
- Club notebooks, 1955-1978 (Box 6)
- General files A-Z and Club notebooks, 1979-1988 (Box 7)